{
  "0": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Adolfo Hohenstein",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "18 March 1854",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "12 April 1928",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Adolfo Hohenstein",
        "date_of_birth",
        "18 March 1854"
      ],
      [
        "Adolfo Hohenstein",
        "origin",
        "German"
      ],
      [
        "Adolfo Hohenstein",
        "date_of_death",
        "12 April 1928"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "1": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Hohenstein",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Italian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Stile Liberty",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Art Nouveau",
        "MISC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "2": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Giovanni Mario Mataloni",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Leopoldo Metlicovitz",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Italian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Leonetto Cappiello",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Marcello Dudovich",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Marcello Dudovich",
        "origin",
        "Italian"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "3": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Julius",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Saint Petersburg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Adolfo Hohenstein",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Laura Irack",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Russian Empire",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Julius",
        "parent_of",
        "Adolfo Hohenstein"
      ],
      [
        "Adolfo Hohenstein",
        "born_in",
        "Saint Petersburg"
      ],
      [
        "Adolfo Hohenstein",
        "child_of",
        "Julius"
      ],
      [
        "Adolfo Hohenstein",
        "child_of",
        "Laura Irack"
      ],
      [
        "Laura Irack",
        "married_to",
        "Julius"
      ],
      [
        "Julius",
        "married_to",
        "Laura Irack"
      ],
      [
        "Laura Irack",
        "parent_of",
        "Adolfo Hohenstein"
      ],
      [
        "Adolfo Hohenstein",
        "born_in",
        "Russian Empire"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "5": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Vienna",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Adolfo",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Adolfo",
        "lived_in",
        "Vienna"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Adolfo",
        "moved",
        "to Vienna where he grew up and completed his studies"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "grew",
        " Vienna"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "completed",
        "his studies Vienna"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "6": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "India",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "decorated",
        "the houses of the local nobility India"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "7": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Italy",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1879",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Milan",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "settled",
        " In 1879 in Milan , Italy"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "8": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "La Scala",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "became",
        "a set and costume designer for La Scala and other theatres"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "9": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Giulio Ricordi",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Ricordi Graphical Workshops",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Ricordi Graphical Workshops",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1889",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Giulio Ricordi",
        "employee_of",
        "the Ricordi Graphical Workshops"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "met",
        "the musical publisher Giulio Ricordi There"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "began",
        "to work for the Ricordi Graphical Workshops , where he shortly became the artistic director in charge of the graphical part in 1889 There"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "work",
        "for the Ricordi Graphical Workshops , where he shortly became the artistic director in charge of the graphical part"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "became",
        "the artistic director in charge of the graphical part shortly the Ricordi Graphical Workshops"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "10": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Campari",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Corriere della Sera",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "La Bohème",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Buitoni",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Tosca",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "created",
        "the posters for La Bohème and Tosca , as well as publicity for Campari , Buitoni and Corriere della Sera , numerous postcards , covers for scores and booklets"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "11": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Falstaff",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1904",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Madama Butterfly",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Le Villi",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Giacomo Puccini",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Giuseppe Verdi",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "1893",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1884",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Giuseppe Verdi's",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "12": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Giovanni Mario Mataloni",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Leopoldo Metlicovitz",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Ricordi",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Marcello Dudovich",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "had",
        "as colleague Giovanni Mario Mataloni and as students Leopoldo Metlicovitz and Marcello Dudovich At Ricordi 's"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "13": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Katharina Plaskuda",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Milan",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1906",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Esposizione per il Traforo del Sempione",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the \"Esposizione per il Traforo del Sempione\"",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "Italy",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the first years of the 1900s",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Bonn",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Düsseldorf",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "the \"Esposizione per il Traforo del Sempione\"",
        "married_to",
        "Katharina Plaskuda"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "marrying",
        "Katharina Plaskuda , a widow"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "traveled",
        "between Italy and Germany till 1906 , when , after winning the competition for the graphical symbol and the poster for the \" Esposizione per il Traforo del Sempione \" , he left Milan for Bonn and Düsseldorf definitively"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "winning",
        "the competition for the graphical symbol and the poster for the \" Esposizione per il Traforo del Sempione \""
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "left",
        "Milan for Bonn after winning the competition for the graphical symbol and the poster for the \" Esposizione per il Traforo del Sempione \""
      ]
    ]
  },
  "14": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Bonn",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1918",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "settled",
        "in Bonn in 1918"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "15": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Renania",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "years",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1911",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "16": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Düsseldorf",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "associated",
        "with the Düsseldorf school of painting"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "17": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Adolfo Hohenstein",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "12 April 1928",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Bonn",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Adolfo Hohenstein",
        "died_in",
        "Bonn"
      ],
      [
        "Adolfo Hohenstein",
        "date_of_death",
        "12 April 1928"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Adolfo Hohenstein",
        "died",
        " 12 April 1928 in Bonn"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "18": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1899",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Onoranze",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Corriere della Sera",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1898",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Volta",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Cesare Urtis & Co",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "19": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Torino",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "20": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Esposizione d'Igiene",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "1900",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Monte Carlo",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "21": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Monaco",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1900",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "22": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Puccini",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Milan",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "62",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "La Wally",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1901",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "propsPietro Mascagni",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "1894",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Bitter Campari",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Rome",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "1 March 19024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Risurrezione",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Teatro Regio",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Manon Lescaut",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "propsAlberto Franchetti",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Teatro Argentina",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "propsGiacomo Puccini",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "propsFranco Alfano",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Le Villi",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "20 January 18924",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Katalog der Frühjahrs",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Teatro Argentina",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "costumesAlfredo Catalani",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Mascagni",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "16 June – 30 September",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "22 November 18983",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1916",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Schwarzwaldküche",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "95",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Große Berliner Kunstausstellung",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "designsGiacomo Puccini",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Teatro Regio",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "19042",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "16 February 189042",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Germania",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Verdi",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Alfano",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Teatro Costanzi",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Cristoforo Colombo",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1905",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "del Dottor Craveri",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "26 January 189290",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Catalani",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Katalog der Großen Kunstausstellung Düsseldorf",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Biblioteca Nazionale Braidense",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Teatro alla Scala",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Neue Folge",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Franchetti",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Zentralinstitut für Kunstgeschichte",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Teatro Regio",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Kunstpalast",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Edgar",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "49",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "La Bohème",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Großen Kunstausstellung",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "Iris",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "41",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "21 April 188954",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Birra Italia Giacomo Puccini",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Ausstellung",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "propsAlfredo Catalani",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Kunstchronik",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "31 May 18842",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Düsseldorf",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Teatro alla Scala",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Teatro alla Scala",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1912",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "propsRichard Wagner",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Craveri",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Teatro Dal Verme",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1917",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Große Berliner Kunstausstellung",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Loreley",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Wagner",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Tosca",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Mastersingers of Nuremberg",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "14 January 19003",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Munich",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Torino",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "27 May – 8 October",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "9 February 18935",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Esposizioni Riunite",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "Giacomo Puccini",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "van Westerhout",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "40",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3 March – 14 April",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "26 December 188962",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Teatro Costanzi",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Cimbelino",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "7 April 189237",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "MascagniGiacomo Puccini",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "1 February 18963",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "26",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Falstaff",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1906",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "propsGiuseppe Verdi",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Mastersingers",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "13",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1911",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Black Forest",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "originaliNiccolò van Westerhout",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "189357",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "4": {},
  "-1": {}
}