{
  "0": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Alphonse Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Sarah Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "14 July 1939",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Alfons Maria Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "ˈalfons ˈmuxa",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Czech",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Art Nouveau",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "24 July 1860",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Alphonse Mucha",
        "origin",
        "Alfons Maria Mucha"
      ],
      [
        "Alphonse Mucha",
        "origin",
        "Czech"
      ],
      [
        "Alfons Maria Mucha",
        "date_of_birth",
        "24 July 1860"
      ],
      [
        "Alphonse Mucha",
        "lived_in",
        "Paris"
      ],
      [
        "Alfons Maria Mucha",
        "origin",
        "Czech"
      ],
      [
        "Alphonse Mucha",
        "date_of_birth",
        "24 July 1860"
      ],
      [
        "Alfons Maria Mucha",
        "lived_in",
        "Paris"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "1": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "The Slav Epic",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Slavic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "second",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "57",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "twenty",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "between 1912 and 1926",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "produced",
        "illustrations , advertisements , decorative panels , as well as designs , which became among the best - known images of the period"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "returned",
        "to his homeland at the age of 57"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "devoted",
        "himself to a series of twenty monumental symbolist canvases known as The Slav Epic , depicting the history of all the Slavic peoples of the world , which he painted between 1912 and 1926 at the age of 57"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "painted",
        "the history of all the Slavic peoples of the world between 1912 and 1926"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "2": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Czechoslovakia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Czech",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "1928",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "10th",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "presented",
        "the series to the Czech nation on the 10th anniversary of the independence of Czechoslovakia"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "4": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Austrian Empire",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Ivančice",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Moravia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Austrian Empire",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "24 July 1860",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Czech Republic",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Czech Republic",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "born_in",
        "Moravia"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "date_of_birth",
        "24 July 1860"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "born_in",
        "Ivančice"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "born",
        " on 24 July 1860 in the small town of Ivančice in southern Moravia , then a province of the Austrian Empire ( currently a region of the Czech Republic )"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "5": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Ondřej",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Amálie",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Amálie",
        "related_to",
        "Ondřej"
      ],
      [
        "Ondřej",
        "child_of",
        "Amálie"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "6": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Ondřej",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "A.",
        "PER"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "7": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Anděla.Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Amálie",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Alphonse",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Anděla",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Anna",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PER"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Amálie",
        "parent_of",
        "Alphonse"
      ],
      [
        "Amálie",
        "parent_of",
        "Anna"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Alphonse",
        "was",
        "his first child"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "showed",
        "an early talent for drawing"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "9": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Volksschule",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "had",
        "a talent for music also"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "was",
        "an alto singer and violin player"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "completing",
        "Volksschule"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "wanted",
        "to continue with his studies After completing Volksschule"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "continue",
        "with his studies"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "10": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Pavel Křížkovský",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "St Thomas's Abbey",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "St Thomas 's Abbey",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Brno",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Pavel Křížkovský",
        "employee_of",
        "St Thomas's Abbey"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "11": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Leoš Janáček.Křížovský",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Cathedral of St. Peter",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Brno",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the Cathedral of St. Peter and Paul",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Křížovský",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Leoš Janáček",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Paul",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Křížovský",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "not was",
        "able to admit and fund him as he had just admitted another talented young musician"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "admit",
        "him"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "fund",
        "him"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "admitted",
        "another talented young musician just"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "received",
        "his secondary school education the gymnasium in Brno"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "13": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Czech",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "grew",
        " in an environment of intense Czech nationalism in all the arts , from music to literature and painting"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "14": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the Gymnázium Brno",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Gymnázium Brno",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Brno",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Moravian",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "designed",
        "flyers and posters"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "16": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the Academy of Fine Arts",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1878",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Academy of Fine Arts",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "the Academy of Fine Arts",
        "based_in",
        "Prague"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "applied",
        "to the Academy of Fine Arts in Prague In 1878"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "rejected",
        "to \" find a different career \""
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "advised",
        "to \" find a different career \""
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "find",
        "a different career"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "17": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "19",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Empire",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Vienna",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1880",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "traveled",
        "to Vienna , the political and cultural capital of the Empire at the age of 19"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "found",
        "employment as an apprentice scenery painter for a company which made sets for Vienna theaters at the age of 19"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "18": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Vienna",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "discovered",
        "the museums , churches , palaces and especially theaters , for which he received free tickets from his employer While in Vienna"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "received",
        "free tickets from his employer the museums , churches , palaces and especially theaters"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "19": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Hans Makart",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Vienna",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "discovered",
        "Hans Makart , a very prominent academic painter , who created murals for many of the palaces and government buildings in Vienna , and was a master of portraits and historical paintings in grand format"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "20": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "21": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1881",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Ringtheater",
        "FAC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "began",
        "experimenting with photography , which became an important tool in his later work"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "experimenting",
        "with photography , which became an important tool in his later work"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "22": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1881",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "took",
        "a train Later in 1881"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "23": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mikulov",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Moravia",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "arrived",
        "in Mikulov in southern Moravia"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "began",
        "making portraits , decorative art and lettering for tombstones"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "making",
        "portraits , decorative art and lettering for tombstones"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "lettering",
        "for tombstones"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "24": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Emmahof Castle",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Tyrol",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Eduard Khuen Belasi",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Gandegg Castle",
        "FAC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Eduard Khuen Belasi",
        "lived_in",
        "Emmahof Castle"
      ],
      [
        "Eduard Khuen Belasi",
        "lived_in",
        "Gandegg Castle"
      ],
      [
        "Eduard Khuen Belasi",
        "lived_in",
        "Tyrol"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "paint",
        "a series of murals"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "25": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Emmahof",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Brno",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1948",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "27": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Wilhelm Kray",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Venice",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Munich",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Bavarian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Florence",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Belasi",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Milan",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Wilhelm Kray",
        "lived_in",
        "Munich"
      ],
      [
        "Belasi",
        "lived_in",
        "Munich"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "28": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Munich",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the Munich Academy of Fine Arts",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Belasi",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Munich Academy of Fine Arts",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "the Munich Academy of Fine Arts",
        "based_in",
        "Munich"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "school_attended",
        "the Munich Academy of Fine Arts"
      ],
      [
        "Belasi",
        "school_attended",
        "the Munich Academy of Fine Arts"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "29": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "September 1885",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "moved",
        "there in September 1885"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "30": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the Munich Academy",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Munich Academy",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "school_attended",
        "the Munich Academy"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "31": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Leonid Pasternak",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Karel Vítězslav Mašek",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Slavic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Czechs",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Russian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Ludek Marold",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Boris Pasternak",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Karel Vítězslav Mašek",
        "origin",
        "Russian"
      ],
      [
        "Ludek Marold",
        "origin",
        "Slavic"
      ],
      [
        "Ludek Marold",
        "origin",
        "Czechs"
      ],
      [
        "Karel Vítězslav Mašek",
        "origin",
        "Slavic"
      ],
      [
        "Boris Pasternak",
        "origin",
        "Russian"
      ],
      [
        "Ludek Marold",
        "origin",
        "Russian"
      ],
      [
        "Leonid Pasternak",
        "origin",
        "Russian"
      ],
      [
        "Boris Pasternak",
        "origin",
        "Slavic"
      ],
      [
        "Karel Vítězslav Mašek",
        "origin",
        "Czechs"
      ],
      [
        "Leonid Pasternak",
        "origin",
        "Slavic"
      ],
      [
        "Boris Pasternak",
        "origin",
        "Czechs"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "become",
        "friends with a number of notable Slavic artists there , including the Czechs Karel Vítězslav Mašek and Ludek Marold and the Russian Leonid Pasternak , father of the famous poet and novelist Boris Pasternak"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "32": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Czech",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "founded",
        "a Czech students ' club"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "contributed",
        "political illustrations to nationalist publications in Prague"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "33": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "North Dakota",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1886",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Methodius",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Pisek",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Roman Catholic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Czech",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Cyril",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "received",
        "a notable commission for a painting of the Czech patron saints Cyril and Methodius , from a group of Czech emigrants , including some of his relatives , who had founded a Roman Catholic church in the town of Pisek , North Dakota In 1886"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "34": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Munich",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "was",
        "very happy with the artistic environment of Munich"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "wrote",
        "Here I am in my new element , painting to friends"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "36": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "37": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Bavarian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Munich",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "found",
        "he could not remain forever in Munich"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "not remain",
        " forever in Munich"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "38": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Belasi",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Rome",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "travel",
        "either to Rome or to Paris"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "39": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1887",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Belasi",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Belasi",
        "lived_in",
        "Paris"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "decided",
        "to move to Paris in 1887"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "move",
        "to Paris"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "40": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Académie Julian",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "1888",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the following year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1889",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Académie Colarossi",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Académie Julian",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "lived_in",
        "Paris"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "moved",
        "where he enrolled in the Académie Julian and the following year , 1889 , Académie Colarossi in 1888"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "enrolled",
        "in the Académie Julian and the following year , 1889 , Académie Colarossi Paris"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "41": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "42": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Paul Laurens",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Académie Julian",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Académie Julian",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Jean-Paul Laurens",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Jean",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Jules Lefebvre",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Jules Lefebvre",
        "school_attended",
        "the Académie Julian"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "43": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Slavic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Count Belasi",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the end of 1889",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Belasi",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "thirty",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "has_age",
        "thirty"
      ],
      [
        "Belasi",
        "has_age",
        "thirty"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "approached",
        "the age of thirty"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "received",
        "enough education"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "ended",
        "his subsidies"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "arrived",
        "in Paris When"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "found",
        "shelter When he arrived in Paris"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "44": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "rue de la Grande Chaumière",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Crémerie",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Charlotte Caron",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "13",
        "FAC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "lived",
        " in a boarding house called the Crémerie at 13 rue de la Grande Chaumière , whose owner , Charlotte Caron , was famous for sheltering struggling artists"
      ],
      [
        "she",
        "accepted",
        "paintings or drawings when needed in place of rent"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "45": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Czech",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Ludek Marold",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Munich",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Ludek Marold",
        "origin",
        "Czech"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "decided",
        "to follow the path of another Czech painter he knew from Munich , Ludek Marold , who had made a successful career as an illustrator for magazines"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "follow",
        "the path of another Czech painter he knew from Munich , Ludek Marold , who had made a successful career as an illustrator for magazines"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "knew",
        "another Czech painter"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "46": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "La Vie populaire",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1891",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1890",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "weekly",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "La Vie",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "began",
        "providing illustrations for the weekly magazine La Vie populaire , which published novels in weekly segments In 1890 and 1891"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "providing",
        "illustrations for the weekly magazine La Vie populaire , which published novels in weekly segments"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "47": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Guy de Maupassant",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "22 May 1890",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "The Useless Beauty",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "48": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Le Petit Français Illustré",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "made",
        "illustrations for Le Petit Français Illustré , which published stories for young people in both magazine and book form also"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "49": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Prussian War",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Franco",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "the Franco-Prussian War",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "23 January 1892",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "provided",
        "dramatic scenes of battles and other historic events For this magazine including a cover illustration of a scene from the Franco - Prussian War which was on 23 January 1892 edition"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "50": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "was",
        "able to buy a harmonium to continue his musical interests , and his first camera , which used glass - plate negatives"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "buy",
        "and his first camera , which used glass - plate negatives"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "52": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Paul Gauguin",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Tahiti",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1893",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Gauguin",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "became",
        "friends with Paul Gauguin"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "shared",
        "a studio with him when Gauguin returned from Tahiti in the summer of 1893"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "53": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Charles Seignobos",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Scenes and Episodes of German History",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "late autumn 1894",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "German History",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Scenes and Episodes",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "August Strindberg",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "became",
        "friends with the playwright August Strindberg , with whom he had a common interest in philosophy and mysticism In late autumn 1894 also"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "had",
        "a common interest in philosophy and mysticism"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "provide",
        "illustrations for Scenes and Episodes of German History"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "54": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Paris Salon of Artists",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "1894",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Four",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Frederic Barbarossa",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "55": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the Central Library of Fine Arts",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Central Library of Fine Arts",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the early 1890s",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PER"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "received",
        "a medal of honor , his first official recognition"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "added",
        "another important client in the early 1890s"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "56": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1897",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Art Nouveau",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Art et Decoration",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "57": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "La Costume au théâtre",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Eugène Manuel",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "continued",
        "to publish illustrations for his other clients , including illustrating a children 's book of poetry by Eugène Manuel , and illustrations for a magazine of the theater arts , called La Costume au théâtre"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "publish",
        "illustrations for his other clients , including illustrating a children 's book of poetry by Eugène Manuel , and illustrations for a magazine of the theater arts , called La Costume au théâtre"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "illustrating",
        "a children 's book of poetry by Eugène Manuel"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "58": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Sarah Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the end of 1894",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "French",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "began",
        "to work for French stage actress Sarah Bernhardt when"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "work",
        "for French stage actress Sarah Bernhardt"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "59": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "26 December",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Lemercier",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Gismonda",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Maurice de Brunhoff",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "described",
        "it later"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "60": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "31 October 1894",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Martin",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "the Boulevard Saint-Martin",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "the Théâtre de la Renaissance",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Boulevard Saint",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Théâtre de la Renaissance",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Victorien Sardou",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "61": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1 January 1895",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Christmas",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "62": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Lemercier",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "happened",
        " When Bernhardt called"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "be",
        "at the publishing house correcting proofs"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "correcting",
        "proofs"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "63": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Cleopatra",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1890",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Costume au Théâtre",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "had",
        "experience painting Bernhardt already"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "painting",
        "Bernhardt"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "made",
        "a series of illustrations of her performing in Cleopatra for Costume au Théâtre in 1890"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "64": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Le Gaulois",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Christmas",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "fifty centimes",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "Brunhoff",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Gismonda",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "October 1894",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Christmas 1894",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "make",
        "a series of illustrations of Bernhardt in the role for a special Christmas supplement , which was published at Christmas 1894 for the high price of fifty centimes a copy"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "design",
        "the new poster for Bernhardt"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "65": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "a little more than two meters",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "Byzantine",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "66": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "One",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "68": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Byzantine",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "70": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1 January 1895",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "71": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1896",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1895",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "four thousand",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "six-year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "she",
        "ordered",
        "four thousand copies of the poster in 1895 and 1896"
      ],
      [
        "she",
        "gave",
        "a six - year contract to produce more Mucha"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "72": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "F. Champenois",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Gismonda",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "six years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "found",
        "himself quite suddenly famous"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "73": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "twenty",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Champenois",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "three hundred",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Boulevard Saint Michel",
        "FAC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "74": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "monthly",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "gave",
        "a generous monthly salary Mucha"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "75": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1896",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "rue du Val",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Medea",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "François Mansart",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "1898",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Lorenzaccio",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "La Dame aux Camelias",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Hamlet",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "La Tosca",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "rue du Val-de-Grâce",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "three-bedroom",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Grâce",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "François Mansart.Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1899",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "was",
        "able to move to a three - bedroom apartment with a large studio inside a large historic house at 6 rue du Val - de - Grâce originally built by François Mansart"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "move",
        "to a three - bedroom apartment with a large studio inside a large historic house at 6 rue du Val - de - Grâce originally built by François Mansart"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "designed",
        "posters for each successive Bernhardt play"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "76": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "La Tosca",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "worked",
        "from photographs of Bernhardt sometimes"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "did",
        "for La Tosca"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "77": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "designed",
        "theatrical programs , sets , costumes , and jewelry for Bernhardt In addition to posters"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "78": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "79": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "80": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Waverly",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Chandon",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Trappestine",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Lefèvre-Utile",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Moët-Chandon",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Lefèvre",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Beers of the Meuse",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Moët",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Nestlé",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Utile",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Beers of the Meuse",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Idéal Chocolate",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Ruinart Champagne",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Waverly and Perfect",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "JOB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Ruinart",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "designed",
        "posters for JOB cigarette papers , Ruinart Champagne , Lefèvre - Utile biscuits , Nestlé baby food , Idéal Chocolate , the Beers of the Meuse , Moët - Chandon champagne , Trappestine brandy , and Waverly and Perfect bicycles"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "83": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "four",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The Seasons",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1896",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "84": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1897",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Reverie",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Champenois",
        "MISC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "produced",
        "an individual decorative panel of a young woman in a floral setting , called Reverie , for Champenois In 1897"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "86": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1897",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Léon Deschamps",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "La Plume",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "87": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1899",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "The Flowers, The Arts",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1900",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "The Flowers",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "The Seasons",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "1902",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Precious Stones",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "The Arts",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "1898",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Seasons",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "The Moon and the Stars",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "The Times of Day",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "88": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "over one hundred",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Champenois",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Between 1896 and 1904",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "created",
        "over one hundred poster designs for Champenois Between 1896 and 1904"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "89": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Japanese",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "90": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1897",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Carlo",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Monte",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Salon des Cent",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1896",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "448",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Monaco",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Monaco",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Monte-Carlo",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Deschamps",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Monaco-Monte-Carlo",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "show",
        "his work in 1896 in the Salon des Cent exhibition"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "have",
        "a major retrospective in the same gallery showing 448 works in 1897"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "91": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "La Plume",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Munich",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Brussels",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "London",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "New York",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Vienna",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "92": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "The Paris Universal Exposition of 1900",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Art Nouveau",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Paris Universal Exposition of 1900",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Vienna",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "move",
        "toward the large - scale historical paintings which he had admired in Vienna"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "admired",
        "the large - scale historical paintings in Vienna"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "93": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Czech",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "94": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "French",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "95": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Sarah Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Moravia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Czech",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "La France",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "origin",
        "Czech"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "was",
        "a Czech from Moravia"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "96": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Austrian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Exposition",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "Herzegovina",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "the Pavilion of Bosnia and Herzegovina",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Pavilion of Bosnia",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "applied",
        "to the Austrian government"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "received",
        "a commission to create murals for the Pavilion of Bosnia and Herzegovina at the Exposition"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "97": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Austria",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Turkey",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Treaty of Berlin",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "the Treaty of Berlin",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "1878",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "98": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "more than twelve meters",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Exposition",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "99": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Slavic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PER"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "100": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Austrian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "World 's Fair",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "a World's Fair",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "101": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Orthodox Christians",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Balkans",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Orthodox",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Christians",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Catholic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Muslims",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "changed",
        "his project to depict a future society in the Balkans where Catholic and Orthodox Christians and Muslims lived in harmony together"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "began",
        "work"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "102": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Balkans",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Balkan",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "departed",
        " immediately"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "make",
        "sketches of Balkan costumes , ceremonies and architecture which he put into his new work"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "put",
        "sketches of Balkan costumes , ceremonies and architecture into his new work"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "103": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Bosnia Offers Her Products to the Universal Exposition",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Bosnia Offers Her Products",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Universal Exposition",
        "MISC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "104": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Bosnians",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "include",
        "some images of the sufferings of the Bosnians under foreign rule which appear in the arched band at the top of the mural"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "107": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Bosnia Pavilion.His",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Exposition",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "Bosnia Pavilion",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "designed",
        "a menu for the restaurant of the Bosnia Pavilion In addition to the murals"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "108": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Austrian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Exposition",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "Bosnian",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Bosnian pavilion",
        "FAC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "designed",
        "the posters for the official Austrian participation in the Exposition , the menu for the restaurant at the Bosnian pavilion , and menu for the official opening banquet"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "109": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Georges Fouquet",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Houbigant",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "produced",
        "displays for the jeweler Georges Fouquet and the perfume maker Houbigant"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "110": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Austrian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Austrian Pavilion",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "the Austrian Pavilion",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Grand Palais",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "French",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "the Grand Palais.His",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Exposition",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "French Government",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Franz Joseph",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Knight of the Order of Franz Joseph",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Knight of the Order",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Legion of Honour",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "the Legion of Honour",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Le Pater",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "111": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Exposition",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "proposed",
        "another unusual project During the course of the Exposition"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "112": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the Eiffel Tower",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "French",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Exposition",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "Eiffel Tower",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "113": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Exposition",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "proposed",
        "that , after the Exposition , the top of the tower should be replaced by a sculptural monument to humanity be constructed on the pedestal"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "114": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the Eiffel Tower",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Eiffel Tower",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Parisians",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Exhibit",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "115": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "116": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Documents Decoratifs",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1902",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "117": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Sarah Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Medea",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Georges Fouquet",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1899",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "collaborated",
        "with the jeweler Georges Fouquet to make a bracelet for Sarah Bernhardt in the form of a serpent , made of gold and enamel , similar to the costume jewelry Bernhardt wore in Medea In 1899"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "make",
        "a bracelet for Sarah Bernhardt in the form of a serpent , made of gold and enamel , similar to the costume jewelry Bernhardt wore in Medea"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "118": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Jiri Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "119": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Art Nouveau",
        "MISC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "120": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1900",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Fouquet",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Cascade",
        "PRODUCT"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "121": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Rue Royale",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Fouquet",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "6 Rue Royale",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Maxim 's",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Exposition",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "1900 Exposition",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Maxim's",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1900",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "122": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "asked",
        "to design the interior Mucha"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "design",
        "the interior"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "123": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "125": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Art Nouveau",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "1901",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Salon",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Nouveau",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Art Nouveau",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Salon",
        "founded_in",
        "1901"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "126": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1923",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "127": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the Carnavalet Museum",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1949",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Carnavalet Museum",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "1914",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "the Carnavalet Museum",
        "based_in",
        "Paris"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "128": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1902",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "seventy-two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Librarie Centrale des Beaux-arts",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Librarie Centrale des Beaux",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Documents Decoratifs",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "130": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Academy Colarossi",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Academy Colarossi",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "about 1900",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "begun",
        "to teach at the Academy Colarossi , where he himself had been a student when he first arrived in Paris In about 1900"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "teach",
        " at the Academy Colarossi , where he himself had been a student when he first arrived in Paris"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "arrived",
        "in Paris first"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "131": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "132": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "made",
        "a considerable income from his theatrical and advertising work"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "wished",
        "to be recognized as a serious artist and philosopher"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "recognized",
        "as a serious artist and philosopher"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "133": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Catholic",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "was",
        "a devoted Catholic"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "was",
        "interested in mysticism also"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "134": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "January 1898",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Grand Orient de France",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the Grand Orient de France",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "the Grand Orient de France",
        "based_in",
        "Paris"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "joined",
        "the Paris masonic lodge of the Grand Orient de France In January 1898"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "135": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Exposition",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "1900",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1900 Exposition",
        "MISC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "wrote",
        " in his memoirs"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "139": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Pater Noster",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Pater Noster",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Lord 's Prayer",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "140": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "\"Le Pater",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Henri Piazza",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "First",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "only 510",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "20 December 1899",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Le Pater",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "approached",
        "his publisher , Henri Piazza"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "proposed",
        "the book"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "141": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Austrian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Exposition",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "1900",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1900 Exposition",
        "MISC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "142": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the New York Sun",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "New York Sun",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "5 January 1900",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Le Pater",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "considered",
        "Le Pater to be his printed masterpiece"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "referred",
        "to it as a work into which he had \" put his soul \" in the New York Sun of 5 January 1900"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "put",
        "his soul a work"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "143": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Charles Masson",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Art et Decoration",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Charles Masson",
        "employee_of",
        "Art et Decoration"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "144": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the United States",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "New York",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "March 1904",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "United States",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "sailed",
        " In March 1904"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "145": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "The Slav Epic",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Exposition",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "1900",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1900 Exposition",
        "MISC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "conceived",
        "his grand project , The Slav Epic during the 1900 Exposition"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "146": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Salomon de Rothschild",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Baroness Salomon de Rothschild",
        "PER"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "had",
        "letters of introduction from Baroness Salomon de Rothschild"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "147": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Sarah Bernhardt's",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "American",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1896",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the United States",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "New York",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Sarah Bernhardt",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "United States",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "landed",
        " When in New York"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "was",
        "a celebrity already in the United States"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "148": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "New York",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Central Park",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "rented",
        "a studio near Central Park , in New York"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "made",
        "portraits"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "gave",
        "interviews and lectures"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "149": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Pan",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Slavic",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Pan-Slavic",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "made",
        "contact with Pan - Slavic organizations also"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "150": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "New York City",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Slavic",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Pan-Slavic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Charles Richard Crane",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Slavophile",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Pan",
        "MISC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "met",
        "Charles Richard Crane , a wealthy businessman and philanthropist , who was a passionate Slavophile At one Pan - Slavic banquet in New York City"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "151": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Slavic",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "commissioned",
        "to make a portrait of his daughter in a traditional Slavic style Mucha"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "make",
        "a portrait of his daughter in a traditional Slavic style"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "152": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Slavic",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "shared",
        "Mucha 's enthusiasm for a series of monumental paintings on Slavic history"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "became",
        "Mucha 's most important patron"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "153": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Slavia",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Crane",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "100 koruna",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "Czechoslovak",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "designed",
        "the Czechoslovak bills When"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "used",
        "his portrait of Crane 's daughter as the model for Slavia for the 100 koruna bill When Mucha designed the Czechoslovak bills"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "154": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "America",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "New York",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Moravia",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "wrote",
        "You must have been very surprised by my decision to come to America , perhaps even amazed to his family in Moravia"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "156": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "America",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "France",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the end of May 1904",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "\"He",
        "PER"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "157": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1905",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "four",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "between 1905 and 1910",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "five to six months",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "early",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "New York",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "finished",
        "his commissions"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "returned",
        "to New York in early January 1905"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "made",
        "four more trips between 1905 and 1910"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "staying",
        " for five to six months"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "158": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Marie / Maria",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Chytilová",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "10 June 1906",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "New York",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1906",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "(Marie/Maria) Chytilová",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "(Marie/Maria) Chytilová",
        "lived_in",
        "New York"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "returned",
        "to New York In 1906"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "married",
        "his new wife ,  on 10 June 1906 in Prague"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "159": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1909",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "U.S.",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "remained",
        "in the U.S. until 1909"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "160": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "New York School of Applied Design for Women",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Art Institute of Chicago",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the United States",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1909.His",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Art Institute of Chicago",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the New York School of Applied Design for Women",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Philadelphia School of Art",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "New York",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Philadelphia School of Art",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "five weeks",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Jaroslava",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "United States",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Jaroslava",
        "lived_in",
        "the United States"
      ],
      [
        "Jaroslava",
        "date_of_birth",
        "1909.His"
      ],
      [
        "Jaroslava",
        "born_in",
        "New York"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "taught",
        "illustration and design for five weeks at the Philadelphia School of Art"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "became",
        "a visiting professor at the Art Institute of Chicago"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "161": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Savon Mucha",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1906",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "rejected",
        "most commercial proposals"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "accepted",
        "one proposal in 1906"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "162": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Art Nouveau",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "German Theater of New York",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "the German Theater",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Comedy and Truth",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1908",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "New York",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "undertook",
        "one large decoration project , for the interior of the German Theater of New York In 1908"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "produced",
        "three large allegorical murals , in the Art Nouveau style , representing Tragedy , Comedy and Truth"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "163": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "one year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the German Theater",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Artistically",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "1909",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "German Theater",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "made",
        "graphic designs , stage and costume designs Besides the decoration"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "164": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "American",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "The American Sarah Bernhardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Maude Adams",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Leslie Carter",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Broadway",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "The American",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Sarah Bernhardt",
        "PER"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "made",
        "posters for the American actress Mrs. Leslie Carter "
      ]
    ]
  },
  "165": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "America",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Josephine Crane Bradley",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Slavia",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Slavic",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "166": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Slav Epic",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "the Slav Epic",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Crane",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "167": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Slavic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "lived_in",
        "Paris"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "never given",
        "his dream of being a history painter During his long stay in Paris"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "being",
        "a history painter"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "illustrate",
        "accomplishments of the Slavic peoples of Europe"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "168": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the Slav Epic",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1909",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Charles Crane",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "February 1910",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Slav Epic",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "1908",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "completed",
        "his plans for the Slav Epic in 1908 and 1909"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "169": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1909",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "170": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the Austrian Empire",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Austrian Empire",
        "MISC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "made",
        "the decision to return to his old country , still then part of the Austrian Empire"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "171": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1910",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "\"His",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "Slav",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "wrote",
        "I will be able to do something really good , not just for the art critic but for our Slav souls to his wife"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "172": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "173": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Lord Mayor 's Hall",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "the Lord Mayor's Hall",
        "FAC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "decorated",
        "the Lord Mayor 's Hall while the other artists decorated the other rooms"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "174": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "European",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Slavic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Slavs",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "designed",
        "a series of large - scale murals for the domed ceiling and walls with athletic figures in heroic poses , depicting the contributions of Slavs to European history over the centuries , and the theme of Slavic unity"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "created",
        "a series of large - scale murals for the domed ceiling and walls with athletic figures in heroic poses , depicting the contributions of Slavs to European history over the centuries , and the theme of Slavic unity"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "175": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "The Slav Epic",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Slavic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "1911",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Slav Epic",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Lord Mayor's Hall",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Parisian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Lord Mayor 's Hall",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "was",
        "able to devote his attention to what he considered his most important work ; The Slav Epic , a series of large paintings illustrating the achievements of the Slavic peoples over history"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "devote",
        "his attention to what he considered his most important work ; The Slav Epic , a series of large paintings illustrating the achievements of the Slavic peoples over history"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "considered",
        "his most important work"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "176": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Slavic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Czechs",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Hungarians",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "ten",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Balkans",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "twenty",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Russians",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Orthodox",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Mount Athos",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Bulgarians",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Serbs",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Poles",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "177": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "eight meters",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "178": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1928.While",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Bohemia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Paris Mucha",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "the Zbiroh Castle",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Zbiroh Castle",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "paint",
        "them"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "rented",
        "an apartment and a studio in the Zbiroh Castle in western Bohemia , where he lived and worked until 1928.While living in Paris"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "lived",
        " until 1928.While the Zbiroh Castle in western Bohemia"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "worked",
        " until 1928.While the Zbiroh Castle in western Bohemia"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "imagined",
        "the series as \" light shining into the souls of all people with its clear ideals and burning warnings"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "179": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Poland",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Slavic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Balkans",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "prepare",
        "the project"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "traveled",
        "to all the Slavic countries , from Russia and Poland to the Balkans making sketches and taking photographs"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "making",
        "sketches"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "taking",
        "photographs"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "181": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "twenty",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "between 1912 and 1926",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "used",
        "egg tempera paint , which , according to his research , was quicker - drying and more luminous , and would last longer"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "created",
        "the twenty canvases between 1912 and 1926"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "182": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the First World War",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "France",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "First World War",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Austrian Empire",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "the Austrian Empire",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "worked",
        " throughout the First World War , when the Austrian Empire was at war with France , despite wartime restrictions , which made canvas hard to obtain"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "183": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Czechoslovak Republic",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "continued",
        "his work after the war ended , when the new Czechoslovak Republic was created"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "184": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Czechoslovak Republic",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "the Czechoslovak Republic.Under",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "tenth",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1928",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "donated",
        "his work to the city of Prague in 1928 Under the conditions of his contract"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "185": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Epic",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1919",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Slav Epic",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "1928",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Slav",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "186": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1963 until 2012",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Moravský Krumlov",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "South Moravian Region",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "1928",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Czech Republic",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Czech Republic",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "the South Moravian Region",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "187": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the National Gallery's",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "National Gallery",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Veletržní Palace",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "2012",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "the National Gallery's",
        "based_in",
        "Prague"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "188": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Epic",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Slav Epic",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Czech",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Slav",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "2026.While",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "working",
        "on the Slav Epic"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "did",
        "work for the Czech government also"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "189": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Slavia",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Charles Crane",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "American",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "1918",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Charles Crane",
        "parent_of",
        "Slavia"
      ],
      [
        "Slavia",
        "child_of",
        "Charles Crane"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "designed",
        "the korun bank note In 1918"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "191": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the Lottery of the Union of Southwestern Moravia",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "Lottery of the Union of Southwestern Moravia",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "declined",
        "commercial work"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "make",
        "occasional posters for philanthropic and cultural events , such as the Lottery of the Union of Southwestern Moravia , and for Prague cultural events"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "192": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "The Slav Epic",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Czechoslovakia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Slav Epic",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "1930s",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "193": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Jeu de Paume",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Nazi",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "the 1930s",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Hitler",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "1936",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Slav Epic.Hitler",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Czechoslovakia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Slav Epic",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "139",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Nazi Germany",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "194": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Age of Wisdom",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Age of Reason",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Age of Love",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "from 1936 to 1938",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "began",
        "work on a new series , a triptych depicting the Age of Reason , the Age of Wisdom and the Age of Love , which he worked on from 1936 to 1938 , but never completed"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "worked",
        "on from 1936 to 1938"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "never completed",
        "a triptych depicting the Age of Reason , the Age of Wisdom and the Age of Love"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "195": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the Greater German Reich",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Moravia",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Hitler",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Czechoslovakia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the Protectorate of Bohemia and Moravia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Greater German Reich",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "15 March 1939",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Protectorate of Bohemia",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "196": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Freemason",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Slav",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "origin",
        "Slav"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "197": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "several",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "interrogated",
        " for several days"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "199": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "79th",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "14 July 1939",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "over a month",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Second World War",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "the Second World War",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "10 days",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "contracted",
        "pneumonia"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "died",
        " 10 days short of his 79th birthday and over a month before the outbreak of the Second World War"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "200": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Vyšehrad",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Czech",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Slavín Monument of Vyšehrad",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Slavín Monument",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "201": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Art Nouveau",
        "MISC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "was",
        "for his Art Nouveau work"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "remains",
        "widely known for his Art Nouveau work , which frustrated him"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "known",
        "for his Art Nouveau work , which frustrated him"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "202": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Jiří Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Art Nouveau",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "not think",
        "much of Art Nouveau According to his son and biographer , Jiří Mucha"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "205": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "today",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "took",
        "the greatest pride in his work as a history painter"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "206": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Jiří Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "207": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "208": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "The Slav Epic",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Slav Epic",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "twenty-five years",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Moravský Krumlov",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "209": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "The Slav Epic",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "National Gallery",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha Museum",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "The National Gallery",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Czech Freemasonry",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Czech",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "1998",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Freemasonry.The Mucha Museum",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Mucha",
        "credited",
        "with restoring the movement of Czech Freemasonry"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "restoring",
        "the movement of Czech Freemasonry"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "210": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1982",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Jiří Mucha",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "nine-year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "World No . 1",
        "MISC"
      ],
      [
        "Ivan Lendl",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Ivan Lendl",
        "has_title",
        "1"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "211": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Prague.On",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "24 July 2010",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Google",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "150th",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2013",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Prague",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Alfonse Mucha",
        "PER"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Alfonse Mucha's",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "81": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Champenois",
        "PER"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "created",
        "a new kind of product , a decorative panel , a poster without text , purely for decoration With Champenois also"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "203": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Art Nouveau",
        "MISC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "asked",
        "What is it , Art Nouveau"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "3": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "considered",
        "it his most important work"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "8": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "drew",
        " In the preschool period exclusively"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "12": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "gave",
        "his chorister position After his voice broke"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "played",
        "as a violinist during masses"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "became",
        "devoutly religious"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "wrote",
        "For me , the notions of painting , going to church , and music are so closely knit that often I can not decide whether I like church for its music , or music for its place in the mystery which it accompanies later"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "15": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "found",
        "some employment designing theatrical scenery and other decorations"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "designing",
        "theatrical scenery and other decorations"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "26": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "showed",
        "his skill at mythological themes , the female form , and lush vegetal decoration"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "35": {},
  "51": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "took",
        "pictures of himself and his friends"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "used",
        "it to compose his drawings regularly also"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "compose",
        "his drawings"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "67": {},
  "69": {},
  "82": {},
  "85": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "designed",
        "a calendar with a woman 's head surrounded by the signs of the zodiac also"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "105": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "done",
        "with his theater work"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "took",
        "photographs of posed models often As he had done with his theater work"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "painted",
        " often simplifying the forms"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "simplifying",
        "the forms"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "106": {},
  "124": {},
  "129": {},
  "136": {},
  "137": {},
  "138": {},
  "155": {},
  "180": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "used",
        "costumed models and still and motion picture cameras to set the scenes"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "set",
        "the scenes"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "encouraging",
        "the models to create their own poses often"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "190": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "designed",
        "postage stamps for his new country"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "198": {},
  "204": {},
  "-1": {}
}