{
  "0": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "6 April 1528",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Renaissance",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "English",
        "LANGUAGE"
      ],
      [
        "21 May 1471",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Durer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer",
        "born_in",
        "German"
      ],
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer",
        "date_of_birth",
        "21 May 1471"
      ],
      [
        "Durer",
        "date_of_birth",
        "21 May 1471"
      ],
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer",
        "origin",
        "German"
      ],
      [
        "Durer",
        "origin",
        "German"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer ",
        "spelled",
        "as Durer sometimes"
      ],
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer ",
        "was",
        "a German painter , printmaker , and theorist of the German Renaissance"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "1": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "his twenties",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "born_in",
        "Nuremberg"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "Born",
        " in Nuremberg"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "established",
        "his reputation and influence across Europe in his twenties due to his high - quality woodcut prints"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "2": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Raphael",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Maximilian I.",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1512",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Leonardo da Vinci",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Giovanni Bellini",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Italian",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "origin",
        "Italian"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "was",
        "in contact with the major Italian artists of his time , including Raphael , Giovanni Bellini , and Leonardo da Vinci"
      ],
      [
        "engravings , his preferred technique in his later prints , altarpieces , portraits and self - portraits , watercolours and books",
        "includes",
        "Dürer 's vast body of work"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "3": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Gothic",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "4": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Knight, Death and the Devil",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1514",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1513",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Saint Jerome in his Study",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Melencolia I",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Meisterstiche",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "5": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "European",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "His watercolours",
        "mark",
        "him as one of the first European landscape artists while his woodcuts revolutionised the potential of that medium"
      ],
      [
        "his woodcuts",
        "revolutionised",
        "the potential of that medium"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "6": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Northern",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Northern Renaissance",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Italian",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's introduction of classical motifs into Northern art",
        "secured",
        "his reputation as one of the most important figures of the Northern Renaissance"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "8": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer the Elder",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1467",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "eighteen",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "third",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Barbara Holper",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "21 May 1471",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "second",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "child_of",
        "Barbara Holper"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "child_of",
        "Albrecht Dürer the Elder"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "date_of_birth",
        "21 May 1471"
      ],
      [
        "Barbara Holper",
        "married_to",
        "Albrecht Dürer the Elder"
      ],
      [
        "Barbara Holper",
        "parent_of",
        "Dürer"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "born",
        " on 21 May 1471"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer the Elder and Barbara Holper",
        "married",
        " in 1467"
      ],
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer the Elder and Barbara Holper",
        "had",
        "eighteen children together"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "9": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer the Elder",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Ajtós",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Albrecht Ajtósi",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1455",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Hungary",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Gyula",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Albrecht Ajtósi",
        "lived_in",
        "Hungary"
      ],
      [
        "Albrecht Ajtósi",
        "lived_in",
        "Gyula"
      ],
      [
        "Albrecht Ajtósi",
        "lived_in",
        "Nuremberg"
      ],
      [
        "Albrecht Ajtósi",
        "lived_in",
        "Ajtós"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer the Elder ",
        "was",
        "a successful goldsmith who by 1455 had moved to Nuremberg from Ajtós , near Gyula in Hungary"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "10": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Holper",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "married",
        "Holper , his master 's daughter when he himself qualified as a master"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "11": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Albrecht",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "One",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Hans Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Albrecht",
        "sibling_of",
        "Hans Dürer"
      ],
      [
        "Hans Dürer",
        "sibling_of",
        "Albrecht"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "One of Albrecht 's brothers , Hans Dürer",
        "was",
        "a painter also"
      ],
      [
        "One of Albrecht 's brothers , Hans Dürer",
        "trained",
        "under him"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "12": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Albrecht",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Endres Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Albrecht",
        "sibling_of",
        "Endres Dürer"
      ],
      [
        "Endres Dürer",
        "sibling_of",
        "Albrecht"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Another of Albrecht 's brothers , Endres Dürer",
        "took",
        "their father 's business"
      ],
      [
        "Another of Albrecht 's brothers , Endres Dürer",
        "was",
        "a master goldsmith"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "13": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Hungarian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Ajtósi",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "alternate_name",
        "Ajtósi"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "The German name \" Dürer \"",
        "is",
        "a translation from the Hungarian , \" Ajtósi \""
      ]
    ]
  },
  "14": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Hungarian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Türer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "16": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer the Younger",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Türer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer the Younger",
        "changed",
        "\" Türer \" , his father 's diction of the family 's surname , to \" Dürer \" later"
      ],
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer the Younger",
        "adapt",
        "to the local Nuremberg dialect"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "17": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Anton Koberger",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "child_of",
        "Anton Koberger"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's godfather Anton Koberger",
        "left",
        "goldsmithing in the year of Dürer 's birth"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer 's godfather Anton Koberger",
        "become",
        "a printer and publisher in the year of Dürer 's birth"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "18": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "twenty-four",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "became",
        "the most successful publisher in Germany"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "owning",
        "twenty - four printing - presses and a number of offices in Germany and abroad eventually"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "19": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Latin",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Koberger",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1493",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Nuremberg Chronicle",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "20": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Wolgemut",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1,809",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "21": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "mid-twenties",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Wolgemut.Because",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "worked",
        "on some of these as the work on the project began while he was with Wolgemut"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "was",
        "with Wolgemut"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "left",
        "autobiographical writings"
      ],
      [
        "by his mid - twenties",
        "known",
        "Dürer"
      ],
      [
        "his life",
        "documented",
        " Because Dürer left autobiographical writings and was widely known by his mid - twenties well in several sources"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "22": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "learned",
        "the basics of goldsmithing and drawing from his father After a few years of school"
      ],
      [
        "from his father",
        "drawing",
        ""
      ]
    ]
  },
  "23": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1486",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Michael Wolgemut",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "fifteen",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "his father",
        "wanted",
        "him to continue his training as a goldsmith"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "showed",
        "such a precocious talent in drawing that he started as an apprentice to Michael Wolgemut at the age of fifteen in 1486 Though his father wanted him to continue his training as a goldsmith"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "started",
        "as an apprentice to Michael Wolgemut in 1486"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "24": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Albertina",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Vienna",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1484",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "his later inscription",
        "says",
        ""
      ]
    ]
  },
  "25": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Opus One",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "his oeuvre",
        "define",
        "as deriving from , and always linked to , himself"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "26": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Wolgemut",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "27": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "28": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Italy",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Venice",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Alps",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "29": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "about four years",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Wanderjahre",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "his apprenticeship",
        "completing",
        ""
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "followed",
        "the common German custom of taking Wanderjahre — in effect gap years — in which the apprentice learned skills from artists in other areas After completing his apprenticeship"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "was",
        "to spend about four years away"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "30": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1490",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1492",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Colmar",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Northern Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Martin Schongauer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "left",
        " in 1490"
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "work",
        "under Martin Schongauer , the leading engraver of Northern Europe , but who died shortly before Dürer 's arrival at Colmar in 1492 possibly"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "31": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Netherlands",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Frankfurt",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "where Dürer travelled in the intervening period",
        "is",
        "unclear though it is likely that he went to Frankfurt and the Netherlands"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "travelled",
        "where in the intervening period"
      ],
      [
        "that he went to Frankfurt and the Netherlands",
        "is",
        "likely"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "went",
        "to Frankfurt and the Netherlands"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "32": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Schongauer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Paul",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Ludwig",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Caspar",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Colmar",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Schongauer",
        "sibling_of",
        "Paul"
      ],
      [
        "Paul",
        "sibling_of",
        "Schongauer"
      ],
      [
        "Ludwig",
        "sibling_of",
        "Caspar"
      ],
      [
        "Paul",
        "sibling_of",
        "Ludwig"
      ],
      [
        "Paul",
        "sibling_of",
        "Caspar"
      ],
      [
        "Caspar",
        "sibling_of",
        "Ludwig"
      ],
      [
        "Caspar",
        "sibling_of",
        "Schongauer"
      ],
      [
        "Ludwig",
        "sibling_of",
        "Paul"
      ],
      [
        "Schongauer",
        "sibling_of",
        "Ludwig"
      ],
      [
        "Caspar",
        "sibling_of",
        "Paul"
      ],
      [
        "Schongauer",
        "sibling_of",
        "Caspar"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "by Schongauer 's brothers , the goldsmiths Caspar and Paul and the painter Ludwig",
        "welcomed",
        "Dürer In Colmar"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "33": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Later that year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Basel",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Martin Schongauer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Georg",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "travelled",
        "to Basel Later that year"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "stay",
        "with another brother of Martin Schongauer , the goldsmith Georg"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "34": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Nikolaus Gerhaert",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Strasbourg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1493",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "went",
        "to Strasbourg , where he would have experienced the sculpture of Nikolaus Gerhaert In 1493"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "experienced",
        "the sculpture of Nikolaus Gerhaert Strasbourg"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "35": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "7 July 1494",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "23",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Louvre",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg.Very",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Agnes Frey",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Agnes Frey",
        "married_to",
        "Dürer"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "has_age",
        "23"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "married_to",
        "Agnes Frey"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's first painted self - portrait ",
        "painted",
        " at this time"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer 's first painted self - portrait ",
        "sent",
        "back to his fiancée probably in Nuremberg"
      ],
      [
        "an arrangement made during his absence",
        "following",
        ""
      ]
    ]
  },
  "36": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Agnes",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "37": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Albrecht",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "the Dürer name",
        "died",
        ""
      ]
    ]
  },
  "38": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Albrecht",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Agnes",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Willibald Pirckheimer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Albrecht",
        "married_to",
        "Agnes"
      ],
      [
        "Agnes",
        "married_to",
        "Albrecht"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "by the letters of Dürer in which he quipped to Willibald Pirckheimer in an extremely rough tone about his wife",
        "indicated",
        ""
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "quipped",
        "about his wife to Willibald Pirckheimer the letters of Dürer"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "40": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Agnes",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Pirckheimer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's death",
        "cause",
        " at a young age"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "41": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Albrecht",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "The Men's Bath",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "42": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Italy",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "three months",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "lived_in",
        "Italy"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "left",
        "for Italy Within three months of his marriage"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "43": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Alps",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "made",
        "watercolour sketches as he traveled over the Alps"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "traveled",
        "over the Alps"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "44": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Nemesis",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "others",
        "deduced",
        "from accurate landscapes of real places in his later work , for example his engraving Nemesis"
      ],
      [
        "his",
        "engraving",
        "Nemesis"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "45": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Italy",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Venice",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "went",
        "to Venice In Italy"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "study",
        "its more advanced artistic world"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "46": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Wolgemut",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Schongauer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Housebook Master",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "learned",
        "how to make prints in drypoint and design woodcuts in the German style , based on the works of Schongauer and the Housebook Master"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "47": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Italy",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Italian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "had",
        "access to some Italian works in Germany"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "made",
        "the two visits"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "48": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Venice",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Giovanni Bellini",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "wrote",
        "that Giovanni Bellini was the oldest and still the best of the artists in Venice"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "49": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Lorenzo di Credi",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Andrea Mantegna",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Antonio del Pollaiuolo",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "His drawings and engravings",
        "show",
        "the influence of others , notably Antonio del Pollaiuolo , with his interest in the proportions of the body ; Lorenzo di Credi ; and Andrea Mantegna , whose work he produced copies of while training"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "produced",
        "copies of while training"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "50": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Padua",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Mantua",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "visited",
        "Padua and Mantua on this trip also"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "51": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1495",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "opened",
        "his own workshop On his return to Nuremberg in 1495"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "52": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Italian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "the next five years",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Northern",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "his style",
        "integrated",
        "Italian influences into underlying Northern forms Over the next five years increasingly"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "53": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1496",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the first years",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "The Men's Bath House",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "his best works in the first years of the workshop",
        "were",
        "his woodcut prints , mostly religious , but including secular scenes such as The Men 's Bath House  Arguably"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "54": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "55": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "cut",
        "any of the woodblocks"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "56": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Wolgemut",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "his training in Wolgemut 's studio , which made many carved and painted altarpieces and both designed and cut woodblocks for woodcut",
        "gave",
        "great understanding of what the technique could be made to produce , and how to work with block cutters him evidently"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "57": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "drew",
        "his design"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "glued",
        "a paper drawing to the block"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "59": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Apocalypse",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "sixteen",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1498",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "St. Michael Fighting the Dragon",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "His series of sixteen designs for the Apocalypse",
        "dated",
        "1498 as is his engraving of St. Michael Fighting the Dragon"
      ],
      [
        "his engraving of St. Michael Fighting the Dragon",
        "is",
        ""
      ]
    ]
  },
  "60": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "seven",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "eleven",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Great Passion",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "made",
        "a series of eleven a little later"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "61": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Frederick III",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "The Seven Sorrows Polyptych",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Saxony",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "1496",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "by Dürer and his assistants",
        "executed",
        "The Seven Sorrows Polyptych , commissioned by Frederick III of Saxony in 1496"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "62": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1500.",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1502",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's father",
        "died",
        " In 1502"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "63": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the Life of the Virgin",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "17",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Around 1503–1505",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Around 1503–1505 Dürer",
        "produced",
        "the first 17 of a set illustrating the Life of the Virgin , which he did not finish for some years"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "not finish",
        "the Life of the Virgin for some years"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "64": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "several years later",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Great Passion",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Neither these nor the Great Passion",
        "published",
        " until several years later"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "trained",
        "in the difficult art of using the burin to make engravings himself During the same period"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "66": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the Prodigal Son",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Germanic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "some decades later",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Renaissance",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Italian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Giorgio Vasari",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1496",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Giorgio Vasari",
        "has_title",
        "Renaissance"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "executed",
        "the Prodigal Son , which the Italian Renaissance art historian Giorgio Vasari singled out for praise some decades later , noting its Germanic quality In 1496"
      ],
      [
        "the Italian Renaissance art historian Giorgio Vasari",
        "singled",
        "the Prodigal Son for praise some decades later"
      ],
      [
        "the Italian Renaissance art historian Giorgio Vasari",
        "noting",
        "its Germanic quality"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "67": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Nemesis",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Saint Eustace",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1502",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1498",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "The Sea Monster",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "producing",
        " soon"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "68": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1501",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "69": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Pond in the Woods",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Willow Mill",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "His landscapes of this period , such as Pond in the Woods and Willow Mill",
        "are",
        "quite different from his earlier watercolours"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "71": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Madonnas",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "made",
        "a number of Madonnas , single religious figures , and small scenes with comic peasant figures"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "72": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "73": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Venetian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Venice",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Jacopo de' Barbari",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1500",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Jacopo de' Barbari",
        "origin",
        "Venetian"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "met",
        "The Venetian artist Jacopo de ' Barbari in Venice"
      ],
      [
        "The Venetian artist Jacopo de ' Barbari , whom Dürer had met in Venice",
        "visited",
        "Nuremberg in 1500"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "said",
        "that he learned much about the new developments in perspective , anatomy , and proportion from him"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "learned",
        "much about the new developments in perspective , anatomy , and proportion from him"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "74": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "De' Barbari",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "knew",
        "everything"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "began",
        "his own studies , which would become a lifelong preoccupation"
      ],
      [
        "his own studies",
        "become",
        "a lifelong preoccupation"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "75": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1504",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Adam and Eve",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "77": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1508",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Betende Hände",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "created",
        "large numbers of preparatory drawings , especially for his paintings and engravings"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "78": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1503",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Great Piece of Turf",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1502",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Young Hare",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "continued",
        "to make images in watercolour and bodycolour "
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "make",
        "images in watercolour and bodycolour "
      ],
      [
        "a number of still lifes of meadow sections or animals , including his Young Hare ",
        "including",
        "images in watercolour and bodycolour ( usually combined"
      ],
      [
        "his Young Hare ",
        "including",
        "meadow sections or animals"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "79": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Italy",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "returned",
        "to painting at first producing a series of works executed in tempera on linen In Italy"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "producing",
        "a series of works executed in tempera on linen at first"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "80": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the Adoration of the Magi",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Paumgartner",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "81": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1506",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Venice",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "returned",
        "to Venice In early 1506"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "stayed",
        "there until the spring of 1507"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "82": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's engravings",
        "attained",
        "great popularity By this time"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer 's engravings",
        "copied",
        " By this time"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "83": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Venice",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "San Bartolomeo",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "84": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "of",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Garlands",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "the Adoration of the Virgin",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "This",
        "was",
        "the altar - piece known as the Adoration of the Virgin or the Feast of Rose Garlands"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "85": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Venice",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Italian",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "86": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Prague",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Rudolf II",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "87": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "mid-1507",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1520",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Venetians",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "lived_in",
        "Germany"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "lived_in",
        "Nuremberg"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "returned",
        "to Nuremberg by mid-1507 Despite the regard in which he was held by the Venetians"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "remaining",
        " until 1520 Despite the regard in which he was held by the Venetians in Germany"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "88": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1508",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Adoration of the Trinity",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1511",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Adam and Eve",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Jacob Heller of Frankfurt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Virgin with the Iris",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1507",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "1509",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Frederick of Saxony",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Martyrdom of the Ten Thousand",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1507 and 1511",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Raphael.Between",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Matthaeus Landauer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Assumption of the Virgin",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "His reputation",
        "spread",
        " throughout Europe"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "was",
        "on friendly terms and in communication with most of the major artists including Raphael"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "worked",
        "on some of his most celebrated paintings : Adam and Eve  Between 1507 and 1511"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "89": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1511",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Apocalypse",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Life of the Virgin",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "the Great Passion",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "second",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "completed",
        "two woodcut series , the Great Passion and the Life of the Virgin , both published in 1511 together with a second edition of the Apocalypse series During this period also"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "90": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "post-Venetian",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "91": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1511",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1512",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "thirty-seven",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Little Passion",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "fifteen",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "92": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1513 to 1516",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "Complaining",
        "that painting did not make enough money to justify the time spent when compared to his prints"
      ],
      [
        "to his prints",
        "compared",
        " when"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "produced",
        "no paintings from 1513 to 1516"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "93": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Knight, Death and the Devil",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "St. Jerome in His Study",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Erasmus",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1514",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1513",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Melencolia I",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Handbook of a Christian Knight",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "created",
        "his three most famous engravings : Knight , Death and the Devil  In 1513 and 1514"
      ],
      [
        "the year Dürer 's mother",
        "died",
        ""
      ]
    ]
  },
  "94": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1513",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Pirckheimer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Further outstanding pen and ink drawings of Dürer 's period of art work of 1513",
        "were",
        "drafts for his friend Pirckheimer"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "96": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1515",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Lisbon",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "created",
        "his woodcut of a Rhinoceros which had arrived in Lisbon from a written description and sketch by another artist , without ever seeing the animal himself In 1515"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "97": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Indian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "late as last century",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "98": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1516",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1515",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the years leading to 1520",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "produced",
        "a wide range of works , including the woodblocks for the first western printed star charts in 1515 and portraits in tempera on linen in 1516 In the years leading to 1520"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "99": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1518",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "between 1515–1516",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "sixth",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "His only experiments with etching",
        "came",
        " in this period"
      ],
      [
        "His only experiments with etching",
        "producing",
        "five between 1515–1516 and a sixth in 1518"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "abandoned",
        "a technique as unsuited to his aesthetic of methodical , classical form"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "100": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Maximilian I",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1512",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "101": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Hieroglyphica",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "192",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The Triumphal Arch",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Horapollo",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Pirckheimer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "commissioned",
        "The Triumphal Arch , a vast work printed from 192 separate blocks , the symbolism of which is partly informed by Pirckheimer 's translation of Horapollo 's Hieroglyphica"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "102": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Hieronymous Andreae",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Jörg Kölderer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Johannes Stabius",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "by Johannes Stabius , the architectural design by the master builder and court - painter Jörg Kölderer and the woodcutting itself by Hieronymous Andreae , with Dürer as designer - in - chief",
        "devised",
        "The design program and explanations"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "103": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Hans Springinklee",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Albrecht Altdorfer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1512",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "The Triumphal Procession",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Treitz-Saurwein",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Arch",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "by The Triumphal Procession , the program of which was worked out in 1512 by Marx Treitz - Saurwein and includes woodcuts by Albrecht Altdorfer and Hans Springinklee , as well as Dürer",
        "followed",
        "The Arch"
      ],
      [
        "woodcuts by Albrecht Altdorfer and Hans Springinklee , as well as Dürer",
        "includes",
        "the program of which"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "104": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1808",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Prayer-Book",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Emperor",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "worked",
        "on the marginal images for an edition of the Emperor 's printed Prayer - Book with pen"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "105": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Hans Baldung",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Lucas Cranach the Elder",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's work on the book",
        "halted",
        " for an unknown reason"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "106": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Maximilian",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1519",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Maximilian",
        "date_of_death",
        "1519"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "made",
        "several portraits of the Emperor , including one shortly before Maximilian 's death in 1519"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "107": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Maximilian",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "to be Dürer 's most important patron",
        "turned",
        ""
      ]
    ]
  },
  "108": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "commented",
        "that in Germany , as a non - noble , he was treated as a parasite later"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "treated",
        "as a parasite in Germany"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "109": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Maximilian",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1495",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Pirckheimer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "met",
        "Pirckheimer before entering the service of Maximilian"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "110": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Johannes Stabius",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Hans Tscherte",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Konrad Peutinger",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Conrad Celtes",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Maximilian",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "collaborated",
        "with a great number of other brilliant artists and scholars of the time who became his friends , like Johannes Stabius , Konrad Peutinger , Conrad Celtes , and Hans Tscherte also In Maximilian 's court"
      ],
      [
        "other brilliant artists and scholars of the time",
        "became",
        "his friends"
      ],
      [
        "an imperial architect).Dürer",
        "manifested",
        "a strong pride in his ability ,"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "111": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "One",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "112": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Maximilian",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "took",
        "the charcoal from Maximilian 's hand"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "finished",
        "the drawing"
      ],
      [
        "This is my scepter",
        "told",
        "him"
      ],
      [
        "This",
        "is",
        "my scepter"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "113": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Maximilian",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "the ladder Dürer used",
        "was",
        "too short and unstable"
      ],
      [
        "the ladder Dürer used",
        "told",
        "to hold it for him a noble thus"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "115": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Maximilian",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "August Siegert",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1849",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "make",
        "a noble out of a peasant any day"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "not make",
        "an artist like Dürer out of a noble"
      ],
      [
        "This story and a 1849 painting depicting it by August Siegert",
        "become",
        "relevant recently"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "116": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Vienna",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "nineteenth-century",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "St. Stephen's Cathedral",
        "FAC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "This nineteenth - century painting",
        "shows",
        "Dürer painting a mural at St. Stephen 's Cathedral , Vienna"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "painting",
        "a mural at St. Stephen 's Cathedral , Vienna"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "117": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "seventeenth-century",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Viennese",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "this encounter",
        "corresponds",
        "with the period Dürer was working on the Viennese murals"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "working",
        "on the Viennese murals the period"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "118": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "St. Stephen's Cathedral",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "119": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "120": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Maximilian",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Siegert",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "that this was Maximilian",
        "suggest",
        ""
      ],
      [
        "this",
        "was",
        "Maximilian"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "121": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1505",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1511",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "entered",
        "the emperor 's service in 1511"
      ],
      [
        "they have known and worked with each other earlier than 1511",
        "is",
        "possible"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "122": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Johannes Stabius",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's exploration of space",
        "led",
        "to a relationship and cooperation with the court astronomer Johannes Stabius"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "123": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1515",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Maximilian",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Stabius",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer and Stabius",
        "created",
        "the first world map projected on a solid geometric sphere In 1515"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "124": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Konrad Heinfogel",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1515",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Stabius",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Stabius , Dürer and the astronomer Konrad Heinfogel",
        "produced",
        "the first planispheres of both southern and northerns hemispheres , as well as the first printed celestial maps in 1515 which prompted the revival of interest in the field of uranometry throughout Europe"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "125": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Martin Luther",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Maximilian",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "was",
        "concerned"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "losing",
        "\" my sight and freedom of hand \" perhaps caused by arthritis"
      ],
      [
        "by the writings of Martin Luther",
        "affected",
        "he increasingly"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "126": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "July 1520",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Charles V",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Imperial",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "fourth",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Aachen",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Maximilian",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "made",
        "his fourth and last major journey In July 1520"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "renew",
        "the Imperial pension Maximilian had given him"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "secure",
        "the patronage of the new emperor , Charles V , who was to be crowned at Aachen"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "127": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Rhine",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Antwerp",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Cologne",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "journeyed",
        ""
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "received",
        " well Antwerp"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "produced",
        "numerous drawings in silverpoint , chalk and charcoal Antwerp"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "128": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Madonna of Bruges",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Stefan Lochner",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "s-Hertogenbosch",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Bruges",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Zeeland",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "van Eyck's",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Michelangelo",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Ghent",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Nijmegen",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Cologne",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "attending",
        "the coronation"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "visited",
        "Cologne  In addition to attending the coronation"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "admired",
        "the painting of Stefan Lochner Cologne"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "saw",
        "Michelangelo 's Madonna of Bruges"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "admired",
        "van Eyck 's Ghent altarpiece Ghent"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "129": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "took",
        "a large stock of prints with him"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "wrote",
        "to whom he gave , exchanged or sold them , and for how much in his diary"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "gave",
        "them to whom"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "exchanged",
        "them"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "sold",
        "them"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "132": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Netherlandish",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's Netherlandish diary",
        "reveals",
        "that the trip was not a profitable one also"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "133": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Maximilian",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Margaret of Austria",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Margaret",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "offered",
        "his last portrait of Maximilian to his daughter , Margaret of Austria"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "traded",
        "the picture for some white cloth after Margaret disliked the portrait and declined to accept it"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "134": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Joachim Patinir",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "July 1521",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Quentin Matsys.Having",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Jan Provoost",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Tommaso Vincidor",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Gerard Horenbout",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Jean Mone",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Bernard van Orley",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "he",
        "met",
        "Bernard van Orley , Jan Provoost , Gerard Horenbout , Jean Mone , Joachim Patinir and Tommaso Vincidor During this trip also"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "not meet",
        "Quentin Matsys"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "secured",
        "his pension"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "returned",
        "home in July 1521 having caught an undetermined illness , which afflicted him for the rest of his life"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "caught",
        "an undetermined illness , which afflicted him for the rest of his life , and greatly reduced his rate of work"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "135": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "worked",
        "on a number of grand projects with religious themes , including a crucifixion scene and a Sacra conversazione On his return to Nuremberg though neither was completed"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "137": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the last years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "one consequence of this shift in emphasis",
        "was",
        "that during the last years of his life , Dürer produced comparatively little as an artist"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "produced",
        "comparatively little during the last years of his life"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "138": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Madonna and Child",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1526",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "St. Mark",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Salvator Mundi",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Hieronymus Holtzschuher",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "St. Peter",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "St. John",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "St. Paul",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "only a portrait of Hieronymus Holtzschuher , a Madonna and Child ",
        "was",
        " In painting"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "139": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the Four Apostles",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "100 guilders",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "the City of Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "by Dürer",
        "given",
        "This last great work , the Four Apostles to the City of Nuremberg although he was given 100 guilders in return"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer 's work",
        "restricted",
        "to portraits and illustrations for his treatise As for engravings"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "140": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Philipp Melanchthon",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Frederick the Wise",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Cardinal-Elector",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Willibald Pirckheimer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Erasmus of Rotterdam",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Saxony",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Albert of Mainz",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "141": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Cardinal",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Ulrich Starck",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Melanchthon",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "depicted",
        "the sitters a drawn portrait of the Nuremberg patrician Ulrich Starck"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "142": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Willibald Pirckheimer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "complaining",
        "of his lack of a formal classical education"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "was",
        "greatly interested in intellectual matters Despite complaining of his lack of a formal classical education"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "learned",
        "much from his boyhood friend Willibald Pirckheimer , whom he no doubt consulted on the content of many of his images Despite complaining of his lack of a formal classical education"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "consulted",
        "his boyhood friend Willibald Pirckheimer on the content of many of his images no doubt"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "143": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Erasmus",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "derived",
        "great satisfaction from his friendships and correspondence with Erasmus and other scholars"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "144": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "succeeded",
        "in producing two books during his lifetime"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "145": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Galileo",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1525",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "The Four Books on Measurement",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Kepler",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "146": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1527",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "The other , a work on city fortifications",
        "published",
        " in 1527"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "147": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1528.Dürer",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "The Four Books on Human Proportion",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the age of 56",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "6,874 florins",
        "MONEY"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "his death",
        "died",
        " at the age of 56 leaving an estate valued at 6,874 florins – a considerable sum in Nuremberg"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "148": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Johannisfriedhof",
        "FAC"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "buried",
        "in the Johannisfriedhof cemetery"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "149": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Bernhard Walther",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1509",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1539",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "His large house",
        "purchased",
        "from the heirs of the astronomer Bernhard Walther in 1509"
      ],
      [
        "his workshop",
        "located",
        " where"
      ],
      [
        "his widow",
        "lived",
        " until her death in 1539 where"
      ],
      [
        "His large house ",
        "remains",
        "a prominent Nuremberg landmark"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "150": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Luther",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Catholic Church",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's writings",
        "suggest",
        "that he may have been sympathetic to Luther 's ideas though it is unclear if he ever left the Catholic Church"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "been",
        "sympathetic to Luther 's ideas"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "left",
        "the Catholic Church ever"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "151": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1520",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Martin Luther",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Luther",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Christian",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "wrote",
        "And God help me that I may go to Dr. Martin Luther ; thus I intend to make a portrait of him with great care and engrave him on a copper plate to create a lasting memorial of the Christian man who helped me overcome so many difficulties in his"
      ],
      [
        "Luther",
        "draw",
        " in 1520 in his diary"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "152": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Nicholas Kratzer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1524",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Christian",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "religion",
        "Christian"
      ],
      [
        "Nicholas Kratzer",
        "religion",
        "Christian"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "wrote",
        "\" because of our Christian faith we have to stand in scorn and danger , for we are reviled and called heretics \" In a letter to Nicholas Kratzer in 1524"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "153": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Johann Tscherte",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Albert",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1530",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Luther",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Pirckheimer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "155": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Lutheran",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "March 1525",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Nuremberg City Council's",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "contributed",
        "to the Nuremberg City Council 's mandating Lutheran sermons and services in March 1525 even"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "156": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Andreas Karlstadt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Babylonian Captivity",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1520",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Zwingli",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Erasmus",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Cornelius Grapheus",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Luther",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Melanchthon",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "had",
        "contacts with various reformers , such as Zwingli , Andreas Karlstadt , Melanchthon , Erasmus and Cornelius Grapheus from whom Dürer received Luther 's Babylonian Captivity in 1520 Notably"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "received",
        "Luther 's Babylonian Captivity various reformers , such as Zwingli , Andreas Karlstadt , Melanchthon , Erasmus and Cornelius Grapheus in 1520"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "157": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Catholic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "C. Grapheus",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Erasmus",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "C. Grapheus",
        "religion",
        "Catholic"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "158": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1525",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Lutheran",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "the year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Peasants' War",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "to distance himself somewhat from the [ Lutheran ] movement",
        "seen",
        " the year that saw the peak and collapse of the Peasants ' War"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "159": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Protestant",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's later works",
        "show",
        "Protestant sympathies"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "160": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "The second book",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1523",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Protestant",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "to have an evangelical theme , focusing as it does on Christ espousing the Gospel , as well as the inclusion of the Eucharistic cup , an expression of Protestant utraquism , although this interpretation has been questioned",
        "understood",
        " often"
      ],
      [
        "His 1523 The Last Supper woodcut",
        "have",
        "an evangelical theme"
      ],
      [
        "His 1523 The Last Supper woodcut",
        "focusing",
        "on Christ espousing the Gospel , as well as the inclusion of the Eucharistic cup , an expression of Protestant utraquism although this interpretation has been questioned"
      ],
      [
        "this interpretation",
        "questioned",
        ""
      ]
    ]
  },
  "161": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1526",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "last",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1523",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "St Philip",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "due to Dürer 's uneasiness with images",
        "may",
        ""
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "not was",
        "an iconoclast"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "evaluated",
        "the role of art in religion in his last years even if Dürer was not an iconoclast"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "questioned",
        "the role of art in religion in his last years even if Dürer was not an iconoclast"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "162": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "exerted",
        "a huge influence on the artists of succeeding generations , especially in printmaking , the medium through which his contemporaries mostly experienced his art as his paintings were predominantly in private collections located in only a few cities"
      ],
      [
        "his contemporaries",
        "experienced",
        "his art mostly"
      ],
      [
        "his paintings",
        "were",
        "in private collections located in only a few cities predominantly"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "163": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Raphael",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Titian",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Parmigianino",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "his reputation",
        "spreading",
        " across Europe"
      ],
      [
        "His success in spreading his reputation across Europe through prints",
        "was",
        "an inspiration for major artists such as Raphael , Titian , and Parmigianino , all of whom collaborated with printmakers to promote and distribute their work undoubtedly"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "164": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "His engravings",
        "seem",
        ""
      ],
      [
        "His engravings",
        "had",
        "an intimidating effect upon his German successors"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "165": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the first third of the 16th century",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Northern European",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Lucas van Leyden",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [
      [
        "Lucas van Leyden",
        "origin",
        "Northern European"
      ]
    ],
    "srl": [
      [
        "the only Northern European engraver",
        "continue",
        "to produce large engravings in the first third of the 16th century"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "166": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Giulio Campagnola",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Cristofano Robetta",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Giovanni Battista Palumba",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Marcantonio Raimondi",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Italian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Benedetto Montagna",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Agostino Veneziano",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "The generation of Italian engravers who trained in the shadow of Dürer all",
        "copied",
        "parts of his landscape backgrounds "
      ]
    ]
  },
  "167": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Northern",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Marcantonio",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Alps",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "1515",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's influence",
        "became",
        "less dominant after 1515 , when Marcantonio perfected his new engraving style , which in turn travelled over the Alps to also dominate Northern engraving"
      ],
      [
        "his new engraving style",
        "travelled",
        "over the Alps in turn"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "168": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Italy",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Venice",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Italian",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "had",
        "relatively little influence in Italy , where probably only his altarpiece in Venice was seen"
      ],
      [
        "only his altarpiece in Venice",
        "seen",
        " probably Italy"
      ],
      [
        "his German successors",
        "were",
        "less effective in blending German and Italian styles"
      ],
      [
        "his German successors",
        "blending",
        "German and Italian styles"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "169": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "the 19th and 20th century",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "His intense and self - dramatizing self - portraits",
        "have",
        "a strong influence up to the present"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "170": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "1870 to 1945.The",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "6 April",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Renaissance",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Michelangelo",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the early nineteenth century",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "about 1570 to 1630",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Lucas Cranach the Elder",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Lutheran Church",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Hans Burgkmair",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "never fallen",
        "from critical favour"
      ],
      [
        "significant revivals of interest in his works in Germany in the Dürer Renaissance of about 1570 to 1630 , in the early nineteenth century",
        "been",
        ""
      ],
      [
        "Dürer annually",
        "commemorates",
        " on 6 April along with Michelangelo , Lucas Cranach the Elder and Hans Burgkmair in German nationalism from 1870 to 1945.The Lutheran Church"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "171": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "German",
        "LANGUAGE"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Latin",
        "LANGUAGE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "his theories",
        "communicate",
        ""
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "used",
        "graphic expressions based on a vernacular , craftsmen 's language In all his theoretical works"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "173": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Bible",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Luther",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "contributed",
        "to the expansion in German prose which Luther had begun with his translation of the Bible"
      ],
      [
        "Luther",
        "begun",
        "the expansion in German prose with his translation of the Bible"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "174": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Underweysung der Messung mit dem Zirckel und Richtscheyt",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Instructions for Measuring with Compass and Ruler",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "the Four Books on Measurement",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's work on geometry",
        "called",
        "the Four Books on Measurement "
      ]
    ]
  },
  "175": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "176": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "177": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Libellus super viginti duobus elementis conicis'",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Apollonius",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1522",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Johannes Werner's '",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "draws",
        "on Apollonius , and Johannes Werner 's ' Libellus super viginti duobus elementis conicis ' of 1522 also"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "178": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "second",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "two-dimensional",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "179": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Euclid",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Ptolemy",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "favours",
        "the methods of Ptolemy over Euclid Here"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "180": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "third",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "181": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Vitruvius",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "cites",
        "Vitruvius In architecture"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "elaborates",
        "his own classical designs and columns In architecture"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "182": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Italian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Latin",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "depicts",
        "the geometric construction of the Latin alphabet relying on Italian precedent In typography"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "relying",
        "on Italian precedent"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "183": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Gothic",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "his construction of the Gothic alphabet",
        "based",
        "upon an entirely different modular system"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "184": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "three-dimensional",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "fourth",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "second",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "185": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Archimedean",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Platonic",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "seven",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "discusses",
        "the five Platonic solids , as well as seven Archimedean semi - regular solids , as well as several of his own invention Here"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "186": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1528",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "(Vier Bücher von Menschlicher Proportion)",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "the Four Books on Human Proportion",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's work on human proportions",
        "called",
        "the Four Books on Human Proportion "
      ]
    ]
  },
  "187": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1523",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1512/13",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "188": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "two to three hundred",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Vitruvius",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "based",
        "these constructions on both Vitruvius and empirical observations of \" two to three hundred living persons \" in his own words"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "189": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "1525",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "eight",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "De harmonica mundi totius",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Francesco di Giorgio's",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "second",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "eight further types , broken down not into fractions but an Albertian system , which Dürer probably learned from Francesco di Giorgio 's De harmonica mundi totius of 1525",
        "includes",
        "The second book"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "learned",
        "an Albertian system from Francesco di Giorgio 's De harmonica mundi totius of 1525 probably"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "190": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "third",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "gives",
        "principles by which the proportions of the figures can be modified , including the mathematical simulation of convex and concave mirrors In the"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "deals",
        "with human physiognomy also here"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "191": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "fourth",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "between 1512 and 1528",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "a self - contained essay on aesthetics , which Dürer worked on between 1512 and 1528",
        "Appended",
        "to the last book"
      ],
      [
        "a self - contained essay on aesthetics , which Dürer worked on between 1512 and 1528",
        "is",
        "Appended to the last book"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "worked",
        "on between 1512 and 1528"
      ],
      [
        "that we learn of his theories concerning ' ideal beauty '",
        "is",
        "here"
      ],
      [
        "his theories",
        "concerning",
        "' ideal beauty '"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "192": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Alberti",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "rejected",
        "Alberti 's concept of an objective beauty"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "proposing",
        "a relativist notion of beauty based on variety"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "193": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "believed",
        "that truth was hidden within nature , and that there were rules which ordered beauty still even though he found it difficult to define the criteria for such a code"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "found",
        "it difficult to define the criteria for such a code"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "194": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1512/13",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "his three criteria",
        "were",
        "function  In 1512/13"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "195": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Alberti",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Leonardo",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "196": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1528",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1512",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's belief",
        "developed",
        "from an understanding of human creativity Between 1512 and the final draft in 1528"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "198": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer 's belief in the abilities of a single artist over inspiration",
        "prompted",
        "him to assert that \" one man may sketch something with his pen on half a sheet of paper in one day , or may cut it into a tiny piece of wood with his little iron , and it turns out to be better and more artistic than another 's work at which its author labours with the utmost diligence for a whole year \""
      ]
    ]
  },
  "199": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Etliche Underricht zu Befestigung der Stett, Schloss und Flecken",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Various Lessons on the Fortification of Cities, Castles, and Localities",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1527",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "published",
        "Various Lessons on the Fortification of Cities , Castles , and Localities  In 1527 also"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "200": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Arnhem",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Hieronymus Andreae",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1603",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Johan Janssenn",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "201": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Wechelus",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Italian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Baltic",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Christian Wechel",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "On Cities, Forts, and Castles, Designed and Strengthened by Several Manners: Presented for the Most Necessary Accommodation of War (De vrbibus, arcibus, castellisque condendis, ac muniendis rationes aliquot : praesenti bellorum necessitati accommodatissimae",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Latin",
        "LANGUAGE"
      ],
      [
        "1535",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Wecheli",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Paris.The",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "his designs",
        "had",
        "some influence in the eastern German lands and up into the Baltic region"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "202": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "created",
        "many sketches and woodcuts of soldiers and knights over the course of his life"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "203": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Maximilian I.",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Nuremberg Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Meditation on the Handling of Weapons",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Οπλοδιδασκαλια sive Armorvm Tractandorvm Meditatio Alberti Dvreri",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "1512",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "26-232",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer's",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "His most significant martial works",
        "made",
        " in 1512 as part of his efforts"
      ],
      [
        "his workshop",
        "produced",
        "the extensive Οπλοδιδασκαλια sive Armorvm Tractandorvm Meditatio Alberti Dvreri "
      ]
    ]
  },
  "204": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Hans Talhoffer's",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Berlin Picture Book (Libr.Pict.A.83",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "this time",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Nuremberg",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "Another manuscript",
        "based",
        "on the Nuremberg texts as well as one of Hans Talhoffer 's works , the untitled Berlin Picture Book "
      ],
      [
        "to have originated in his workshop around this time",
        "thought",
        ""
      ],
      [
        "Another manuscript based on the Nuremberg texts as well as one of Hans Talhoffer 's works , the untitled Berlin Picture Book ",
        "originated",
        " around this time in his workshop"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "205": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": [],
    "srl": [
      [
        "his illustrations of grappling , long sword , dagger , and messer",
        "are",
        "among the highest - quality in any fencing manual"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "206": {
    "ner": [
      [
        "Albrecht Dürer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "relations": []
  },
  "7": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "by his theoretical treatises , which involve principles of mathematics , perspective , and ideal proportions",
        "reinforced",
        "This"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "15": {},
  "39": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "He",
        "called",
        "her an \" old crow \""
      ],
      [
        "He",
        "made",
        "other vulgar remarks"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "58": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "his drawings",
        "destroyed",
        " during the cutting of the block Either way"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "65": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "he had begun learning this skill during his early training with his father , as it was also an essential skill of the goldsmith",
        "is",
        "possible"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "begun",
        "learning this skill during his early training with his father as it was also an essential skill of the goldsmith"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "learning",
        "this skill during his early training with his father"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "70": {},
  "76": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "This",
        "is",
        "the only existing engraving signed with his full name"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "95": {},
  "114": {},
  "130": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "This",
        "provides",
        "rare information of the monetary value placed on prints at this time"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "131": {},
  "136": {
    "srl": [
      [
        "This",
        "been",
        "due in part to his declining health , but perhaps also because of the time he gave to the preparation of his theoretical works on geometry and perspective , the proportions of men and horses , and fortification"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "gave",
        "the time to the preparation of his theoretical works on geometry and perspective , the proportions of men and horses , and fortification"
      ]
    ]
  },
  "154": {},
  "172": {},
  "197": {},
  "-1": {}
}